neamb.com 2016-06-01

# Privacy Policy | NEA Member Benefits

## NEA Member Benefits Privacy Policy

**Effective:** January 1, 2014.  
 **Last updated:** July 9, 2015.

**I.  INTRODUCTION**

NEA Member Benefits (“NEA MBC”) values the trust and privacy of National Education Association (“NEA”) members and others. This Privacy Policy sets forth NEA MBC’s practices regarding:  (1) what personal information we collect about you—whether online via the NEA MBC or NEA Academy websites, the websites of our suppliers, via our short messaging services (SMS) or other mobile services or applications, or offline via traditional, hard copy forms and data exchanges from the NEA and NEA MBC’s product suppliers;  (2) how we use that information;  (3) under what circumstances we disclose it;  (4) what choices are available to you regarding such information collection; and  (5) what security we use to protect such information. This Privacy Policy also provides some additional information for users of the NEA MBC and NEA Academy websites.

**II.  DEFINITIONS**

As used in this Privacy Policy, the following terms have the meanings indicated below:  

**A.** The term “we” or “us” means NEA MBC.

**B.** The term “you” means a current or former NEA member or other person who has provided personal information to us in connection with obtaining an NEA MBC product or service (e.g. a person who has participated in an NEA MBC program, someone who has used an MBC Academy product or service, or a person who subscribes to an NEA MBC-produced electronic communication). 

**C.**  The term “personal information” means any piece of information that on its own can specifically identify a current or former NEA member or other person who has provided personal information to us. This would include, but is not limited to, full name, postal address, phone number(s), email address(es), social security number, member ID, financial information, and/or program participation information.

**D.**  The term “NEA MBC website” means NEA MBC’s external website located at neamb.com and any related future websites that we may develop.

**E.**  The term “NEA Academy website” means NEA Academy’s external website located at neaacademy.org, lms.neaacademy.org, and any related future websites that we may develop.

**F.**  The term “NEA MBC-related organizations” means the NEA, the NEA Members Insurance Trust, NEA Foundation, NEA Healthy Futures, NEA Professional Solutions, and any other entity created by or affiliated with NEA MBC or the NEA.

**G.**  The term “third party” means a legal entity that is separate and independent from NEA MBC, its state and local affiliates, or any NEA MBC-related organization.

**H.**  The term “cookie” means a small file that is placed on your computer (or mobile device) that allows a website to store, and sometimes track, information about you and how you use that website or other websites. Cookies, as used by us, are explained in further detail below.

**I.**  The term “discussion forum” means a website component or page that enables users to exchange ideas by posting questions and answers on relevant subjects. Discussion forums are also commonly referred to as “discussion groups,” “discussion boards,” “message boards,” “bulletin boards,” and “online forums.”

**III.  PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED**

We may collect or access personal information about you from the following sources:

**A.**  Personal Information that you voluntarily provide on your NEA/SEA/LEA applications and other NEA MBC forms—whether online via the NEA MBC website, the NEA Academy website, or offline via traditional, hard copy forms (such as but not limited to your name, postal address, telephone number, email address, social security number, etc.).

**B.**  Other Personal Information that you voluntarily provide to us via the NEA MBC website or the NEA Academy website (such as but not limited to an email address if you subscribe to an NEA MBC-produced electronic newsletter or other personal information contained in an email that you send to us via the feedback feature of the NEA MBC website).

**C.**  Personal Information that you provide to us either through SMS, mobile devices, mobile applications or other electronic means, including ancillary data related to such information such as location data, preferences, purchases, and browsing history.

**D.**  Personal Information that we receive from our state and local affiliates or other NEA MBC-related organizations (such as but not limited to your name, postal address, telephone number, email address, Social Security number, etc.).

**E.**  Personal Information that we receive from third parties (such as but not limited to the providers of the courses offered through the NEA Academy, insurance claim information in connection with the NEA Educators Employment Liability Program and publicly available voter registration information).

**IV.  HOW WE USE THAT INFORMATION**

The personal information that NEA and MBC collects or accesses about you helps us improve your experience with the NEA MBC and NEA Academy websites, and allows us and our state and local affiliates and NEA and NEA MBC-related organizations to efficiently and effectively represent you, and provide you with valuable member benefits. This information also allows us and our suppliers to provide products and services to you.

**V.  INFORMATION SHARING**

In order to provide you with efficient and effective representation and member benefits, we routinely share all of the personal information that we collect about you, as described in Section III above, with our state and local affiliates and NEA-related organizations, as well as third parties that perform services on our behalf.

Additionally, we may share any of the personal information that we collect about you, as described in Section III above, with certain third parties NEA MBC has contracted with to provide and/or support the NEA Member Benefits programs available to NEA members, that share our interests, or as otherwise permitted by law. This information, when transmitted via electronic means such as, but not limited to, secured FTP, is encrypted and protected from unauthorized use. 

**VI.  AVAILABLE CHOICES**

Any personal information that you provide to us is voluntary. NEA members may update their personal information at any time. Please contact us at <https://secure.neamb.com/contactus.htm> to update your information. If you subscribe to any NEA MBC-produced electronic communication, whether on-line, mobile/SMS or email based, you may opt out at any time by following the instructions contained in any such communications. If you have any problems, please contact us at <https://secure.neamb.com/contactus.htm>. However, please note that if you do not provide us with certain required information or opt out of the electronic provision of certain information, we (and our partners and suppliers) may not be able to provide you with certain products and services that you desire.

**VII.  CALIFORNIA PRIVACY INFORMATION**

California residents have a right under state law to ask entities with whom they have an established business relationship to provide certain information regarding the sharing of personal information for direct marketing purposes during the past year. NEA MBC will honor such a request coming from any current or former NEA member or other person who has provided personal information to us in connection with obtaining an NEA MBC product or service—whether residing in California or not. Simply submit a request to us at one of the following addresses: [ask-us@neamb.com](mailto:ask-us@neamb.com) or NEA MBC Office of the General Counsel, 900 Clopper Rd., Ste. 300, Gaithersburg, MD 20878-1356, and we will respond within 30 days of receiving your request.

**VIII.  INFORMATION SECURITY **

We maintain administrative, technical, and physical safeguards designed to: (1) provide security and confidentiality of your personal information; (2) protect against any anticipated threats or hazards to the security or integrity of such information; and (3) protect against unauthorized access to or use of such information. For more information on our information security policies, please contact us at <https://secure.neamb.com/contactus.htm> to request a copy of the NEA MBC Information Security Program.

**IX.  ADDITIONAL INFORMATION FOR USERS OF THE NEA MBC AND NEA ACADEMY WEBSITES**

**A.**  Collection and Use of Non-Personal Information

If you use the NEA MBC or NEA Academy websites or mobile applications, you automatically provide us with certain non-personal information in addition to any personal information that you may voluntarily provide. We gather this non-personal information in the aggregate and we share it in the same manner as described in Section V above. For example, if you browse the NEA MBC or NEA Academy websites or download information, our websites automatically record the following non-personal information:

1. The Internet domain for your Internet service (such as “acompany.com” or “acompany.net” if you use a private Internet access account, or “yourcollege.edu” if you connect from a college or university domain);

2. The type of browser that you are using (such as “Mozilla Firefox,” “Google Chrome,” or “Microsoft Internet Explorer”);

3. The type of operating system that you are using (such as Windows, Macintosh, or a mobile device);

4. The date and time that you visit the NEA MBC website and the web pages that you view (including the time spent on each page);

5. Any files downloaded;

6. The address of the previous website that you visited if you linked to us from another website; and

7. The address of the next website that you visit if you link to it from the NEA MBC website.

We use the above non-personal information to diagnose technical problems and track user interests so that we can provide content that interests you. 

**B.**  Children 

The NEA MBC website is a general website, and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to provide us with their personal information.

**C.**  External Links

This Privacy Policy applies only to the NEA MBC and NEA Academy websites. It does not cover any websites that are linked to or from the NEA MBC or NEA Academy websites for which we are not responsible (“linked-sites”). These linked sites will have their own policies and practices which may be different from ours. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the policies and practices of the linked sites especially if you provide personal information to them.

**D.**  Cookies

To enhance your experience on our sites, our web pages use “cookies.” Cookies are small text files that we place in your computer’s (or mobile device’s) browser to store your basic information about you. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your email address or other personal information unless you choose to provide this information to us by registering on our site. Once you choose to provide a web page with personal information, this information may be linked to the data stored in the cookie. We use cookies to understand site usage and to improve the content and offerings on our site. For example, we may use cookies to personalize your experience on our web pages (e.g. to recognize you by name when you return to our site). We also may use cookies to tailor the articles, products and services that are offered to you.

Please note that you can control which cookies you accept. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies or to alert you every time a cookie is offered by a website’s server. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. You can set your browser option so that you will not receive cookies and you can also delete existing cookies from your browser. You may find that some parts of our websites will not function properly and you may not be able to obtain certain products and services if you have refused or limited the use of cookies.

Additionally, NEA MBC allows third parties who advertise or provide content on the NEA MBC and NEA Academy websites to use cookies. Third parties’ use of cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, and is not governed by this Privacy Policy.

**X.  EFFECTIVE DATE, AMENDMENTS, AND CONSENT TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy is effective January 1, 2014. We retain the right to amend or otherwise update this Privacy Policy at any time for any reason. By joining the NEA or using the NEA MBC or NEA Academy websites, you consent to the collection, use, and sharing of personal information as we have described herein. If we amend or update our Privacy Policy, we will post the changes online at the NEA MBC and NEA Academy websites so that you are always aware of NEA MBC’s current practices. Your continued use of our websites constitutes your acceptance of any such revised privacy policies.

**XI.  CONTACT US**

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at <https://secure.neamb.com/contactus.htm>.
